翻译 koki  放 晴  Fatalité  压制 暗之亚瑟王  校对 娃娃 时间 Lucifer
コリオ＝トニス
Colio Tonies, what are humans?
人間とはなんだ？
Beings with the right to gain all the
happiness this world may offer.
この世のすべての幸せを得る権利のある者
Wounded humans are to be saved.
傷ついた人間は助けられればならない
Suffering humans are to be rescued.
苦しむ人間は救われればならない
Forsaken humans are to be loved.
孤独の人間は愛されればならない
Why?
なぜ
All humans are born into
this world to be loved.
すべての人間は愛されるために生まれてきたから
To love and be loved...
To experience fulfillment, never suffering...
愛し　愛され
満ち足り　苦しむことなく
To live a life in utmost bliss...
至上の幸福に包まれた一生を送るために
Then let me ask you this, Colio Tonies:
では　コリオ＝トニス
Why do you do that which you do?
なぜお前はそうしている
コリオ＝トニスは人間ではない
Colio Tonies is not human.
コリオ＝トニスは爆弾だ
Colio Tonies is a bomb.
なぜコリオ＝トニスは生きている？
Why do you exist, Colio Tonies?
In order to kill Hamyuts Meseta.
ハミュッツ＝メセタを殺すため
Yes, kill Hamyuts Meseta.
そう　ハミュッツ＝メセタを殺せ
Kill... Hamyuts Meseta.
ハミュッツ＝メセタを…殺せ
Well now...
さって
And so it begins.
始まり　始まり
The one who stops is foolish
A piece of black wing gently touches fingers
If you were a story
You could still rewrite it all you want
The ink of blood doesn't dry up
No one knows the real us
What changes the chaotic world
What we pursued isn't
Small happiness
Fight with a rumbling heartbeat as a sign
What awaits you is infinite if you
move forward as you wish
Fight off no matter how many
times you get defeated
Engrave your dream onto the scar you bear
In order to connect today's memory that's
on the verge of being buried to tomorrow
Episode 1
Bombs, Books, and a Sinking Ship
第1话 爆弹与书和沉没之船
It seems the new "Meats" you requested from
the Kra District are well on their way.
クラー自治区から取り寄せた新たの「肉」たちも
経過は順調のようだ
Man and God are one and the same.
人と神とは一つのもの
Man has but one duty,
to fulfill his own desire.
ただ一念に己は望みを叶えよう
All is for the glory of God.
すべては神のためである
That is the one, absolute doctrine of the
Church of Drowning in God's Grace.
それこそがわれわれ神溺教団の　唯一にして絶対の教義
And few are as loyal to their own desires.
彼らほど欲望に忠実な存在は
なかなかお目にかかれない
I wouldn't be surprised if a True Man
were to appear among them, though.
彼らの中から「真人」が現れても可笑しくないなっ
With such a vile existence as theirs?
あのように醜い存在が？
They grovel on the floor like cockroaches.
這い蹲り床の温度を知る
It's humiliating.
なんと無様だ
The truth of a True Man cannot
be understood by others.
「真人」の真実とは他者には理解できぬものだよ
Even fellow True Men cannot fully grasp it.
例え　それが「真人」同士でも
You understand, do you not?
君も分かっているだろう
Fascinating...
なるほどねぇ～
Ah, I care not to waste my glorious, fleeting time
on this planet with a senile old man's idle talk.
あー　老い耄れと駄話しなど
私の輝かしい瞬間が無益に過ぎ行くだけだ
Cigal!
シガル！
I shall become a "Book" greater than
all others and ascend into Heaven.
私は誰よりも優れた「本」となり
天国へと召し上げられる
I shall have more pages than any other of you,
with the most lustrous spine ever seen!
お前たちの誰よりも分厚く
誰よりも輝く背表紙
誰よりも幸福な物語を紡ぐ
I shall write the greatest tale
of happiness ever told!
やれ　やれ
Sheesh... He actually thinks
he can go to Heaven.
彼は果たして天国へ行けるかね
The truth of a True Man cannot
be understood by others.
「真人」の真実とは他者には理解できぬもの…だよ
Oops, I may have just understood it.
理解…できちゃったかもよ
What just happened?
どうした？
Is it Armed Librarians?
武装司書か？
Hamyuts Meseta...
ハミュッツ＝メセタ
Good work, Casma!
キャスマさん　お疲れさま
防御結界とはねぇ…
I hate protection barriers...
I guess the Church of Drowning in
God's Grace even has sorcerers!
神溺教団には魔術師までいるんか
Is that a Church of Drowning
in God's Grace ship?
あれが神溺教団の船か？
Your mission, this time, is to investigate
the Church and gather evidence.
今回の指令は教団内の調査と証拠品の押収
And don't forget about freeing the Meats.
忘れちゃいかんよ「肉」たちの解放を
「肉」って呼び方には抵抗があるわ
I'm opposed to calling them that.
だって　元は人…
Because they used to be...
ミレボック　元はじゃない
Milepoc, they didn't "used to be"!
They were and still are human!
彼らは人間だ
I-I know that, Volken. That's why I...
わ…分かってるわよ　ヴォルケン
だからこそわたしは…
Is that...
あれは…
おい　溺れてっぞ
Hey, man overboard!
What? That's bad!
ありゃ　これは大変だ
キャスマ！
Casma!
ほら　とっとと死んでもらえ！
Hurry along and die!
Kill Hamyuts Meseta...
ハミュッツ＝メセタを殺せ…
All True Men are to escape at once!
「真人」の皆様は早くお逃げになってください
Let us False Men handle the rest.
あとは「擬人」のわれわれにお任せを
シガルはどうした
Where's Cigal?
He's gone already.
すでにこちらから
Good grief... Always looking
out for number one.
全く　苦手な奴だ
ハハ　それでこそだよ
You're one to talk.
Open the throttle! We must get in
front of the Silver Smoke!
もっと速度を上げろ
白煙号の前に出るんだ
Milepoc, contact the Acting Chief via telepathy!
ミレボック
代行と「思考共有」を
Okay.
え
Chief, this is Milepoc Finedel. Do you copy?
代行　ミレボック＝ファインデルです
応答をお願います
うん？　なに？　どうした？
Hmm? What is it?
There are Meats jumping overboard,
carrying bombs from the Silver Smoke.
白煙号から爆弾を抱えた「肉」たちが落下
They're launching consecutive kamikaze attacks.
次々に自爆行為を
Ah... They aren't carrying the bombs.
あー　そりゃ抱えてるんじゃないわ
The bombs are embedded inside of them.
爆弾を自家に埋め込まれてる
You could call them human bombs.
人間爆弾っていうやつだね
Human bombs?
人間爆弾？
Board the Silver Smoke and free any
Meats who don't look like they'll detonate.
とっとと白煙号に乗り込んで
爆発しそうにない「肉」だけ解放しなさい
I'm busy right now.
私　今手が離せないの
Chief?
代行？
Understood? Grab every last shred of evidence.
いい　証拠品は残らず押収するのよ
Okay, go get 'em.
じゃ　しっかり働いて
What did the Chief say?
代行はなんと？
She said to go ahead with the mission.
すぐにでも作戦を実行しろと
That's dangerous.
危険だ　もっと慎重に
We should be more cautious.
人間爆弾
Human bombs...
That's it! We're boarding the Silver Smoke!
乗り込むぞ　白煙号へ！
Th-The Armed Librarians are coming at us!
き…来上がったぜ　武装司書が
Damn! We're going to have
to fight those monsters!
くそ　あんな化け物を相手にしなきゃいけないのかよ
What you did to those men...
お前たちが彼らを…
All those inhuman deeds committed by you,
the Church of Drowning in God's Grace,
神溺教団
あらゆる非人道的行為を多くない
you heretics who have decried
the value of love...
あらゆる愛を無価値とする邪教
お前たちは人間じゃない
You're the ones who aren't human!
Go!
行っちゃえ！
Volken.
ヴォルケン
It smells terrible...
この匂い…ひどい
Are those Meats?
「肉」…か？
They treat them like cattle.
本当に家畜扱いだなぁ
Damn. This is heresy!
外道…
They don't seem to be equipped with bombs.
爆弾は付いていないようだ
Come on! Step outside!
さぁ　君たちは外へ
Okay! Hurry!
さぁ　速く
Come on. You, too.
さぁ　君も
Volken!
ヴォルケンさん
What's the matter?
どうした？
More bombs in here, huh?
ここにも爆弾か？
Same thing with those Meats.
「肉」といい
The Church of Drowning in God's Grace
just likes to blow crap up.
神溺教団は爆発したがりなんですね
あっ…や…ええと
No, I mean...
I'm sure the ship's fitted with
more bombs than these.
ほかにも爆弾が仕掛けられてるかもしれない
Get those people off this ship immediately.
今のうちに彼らを連れ出そう
Oh, sure!
あっ…はい
うん？
"Vend Ruga is alive."
ベンド＝ルガーは生きている
"He is living inside Olivia Litlet."
オリビア＝リットレットの心の中に生きている
What is all this?
なんだ　これは？
Olivia Litlet?
オリビア＝リットレット
What a shame. I really thought that
I would end this peacefully.
残念　平和的に済ますようと思ってたげど
I guess that's no longer an option.
そうもいかなくなちゃったわね
Okay, stay in your line.
はいはい　ちゃんと並んでね
Watch your step when boarding.
足元に気をつけて
Volken!
ヴォルケン　救助船は一時間で来るそうよ
The rescue ship said they'd
arrive in an hour.
All right.
そうか
What the hell just happened?
なっ…なにが起こったの？
Hey, where'd the Meats go?
おい　「肉」たちは？
They've given up on life.
生きることを諦めている
They're...
彼は…
Volken!
ヴォルケン
Hold on tight, okay?
しっかり掴まってろよ
待って！　君は助かりたくないのか？
Wait! Don't you want to be rescued?
Why? Why are you just giving up?!
なぜだ？なぜ助かろうとしない？
この手を掴めば…
You just have to grab my hand...
Don't you want to survive?!
生きたくないのか
Volken, there's gonna be another explosion.
ヴォルケン
また爆発するわ
早く離きゃ…
We have to get out of...
Don't you want to live?!
生きたくないのか？！
That wasn't exactly subtle, Hamy.
ずいぶん派手に遣らかしたなぁ ハミュ
What can I say?
まぁーね
I've been called many names.
私は多くの名前で呼ばれました
A nation's saint.
「救国の聖女」
An ever-laughing witch.
「常笑いの魔女」
Once, it was even a cute name like Calico.
一つ　「三毛猫」になんて可愛らしいなぁって呼ばれたことがありましたが
But, in the end, I long to be
called by my real name.
わたしはやはり本当の名前で呼ばれたい
When my words reach you,
私の言葉が届く時
please go to the place where someone
precious lost someone precious to them.
大切な人が大切な人を失った場所に行ってください
In that brief moment,
when the wind lets up,
ほんの片時　風が止む一瞬
run straight there.
迷わずに走ってください
For I...
私は…
Okay, okay! Line up! No pushing.
はいはい　並んで並んで
押さないでね
あっ　サイン　まいたなぁ
My autograph? How can I refuse?
ノロティ
Do you have a pen on you, Noloty?
ペンある？　ペン
A pen!
キャサリロさん
Kyasariro!
We don't have time for that right now.
それどころじゃないです
こっちも手伝ってくださいよ
Please come and help me!
Hey, hey.
こらこら
Don't get careless just because you're busy.
忙しいからって横着しちゃだめ
イレイアさん
Ireia!
After our lives come to a close and we're
buried deep within the earth,
人がその命を閉じた時
地中に埋められた魂は化石となり
our souls fossilize and become Books.
やがて「本」へと変わる
Each of these Books contains the
record of someone's entire life.
この「本」の一つ一つには
一人一人の記憶がすべて納められているわ
Our duty, as Armed Librarians,
is to manage and protect them.
あたしたち武装司書は　その「本」を管理し守ることの役名
だからこそ皆さんあたしたちをこれだけ慕ってくれているの
It is for this reason that we
are so highly regarded.
Think of what would happen if
one of the Books should break.
もし「本」を壊してでも見なさい
That would be like giving that
Book's author a second death.
それは「本」の主に　二度目の死を与えるとも同じことなのよ
Right.
はい
Noloty, I need that pen! The pe...
ノロティ
ぺんだってば　ぺ…
イレイア教官
Mrs. Ireia.
Dragon Pneumonia germs...
龍骸咳の病原体
One of the seven war-machines of the past,
the spinning fairy Ylucklucu...
七つの追憶の戦機の一つ
「自転人形ユックユック」
But we didn't find the Church clergyman's
Book we were looking for.
最もお目当ての神溺教団員の「本」は
見つからなかったな
I figured we'd be able to unravel the
Church of Drowning in God's Grace's
欠片の一つでもありゃ
神溺教団の謎に迫れると思ったんじゃなぁ
mysteries if we just had a fragment...
What are you talking about? We got one
of their top echelon leader's Books.
なに言ってるの？
大幹部の「本」が見つかったじゃない
The piece contains Shiron Byacornise, the witch
with the magic, ever-laughing blade.
常笑いの魔剣を持つ魔女
シロン＝ブーヤコーニッシュの欠片が
We can find as many Books belonging to people
of the past that we want, but...
過去の人間の「本」がいくら見つかったところで…
The past shines yet more
radiant than the present.
現在より輝く過去がある
Isn't that why we're here in the first place?
だからこそ　私らの存在意義があるでしょう
お茶の時間よ
Tea time!
There you go.
はい　どうぞ
Oh, Volken!
あ　ヴォルケン
There's honey, too.
蜂蜜があるげと
I'm not a child!
僕は子どもではありません
Okay, okay.
はいはい
代行　その魔女とは？
Chief, that witch you mentioned...
Touch the fragment and see for yourself.
触ってみりゃ分かるわよ
あっ　なんてひどーな
That's downright inhuman!
Milepoc, recite your history lesson.
ミレポ　歴史のお勉強よ
Certainly.
はい
Dragon Pneumonia was an illness that infected
the people of the Ronar Dukedom 280 years ago.
２８０年前ロナ王国に蔓延した病　龍骸咳
It is said that the only person who knew how
to create the cure was Shiron Byacornise.
その特効薬の製造法をただ一人知っていたのが
シロン＝ブーヤコーニッシュであったと伝えられています
She spread the disease across the land and
extorted incredible profit by selling the cure.
彼女は龍骸咳を蔓延させ
特効薬と引き換えに暴利を貪り
With the magic sword Shlamuffen,
she slew all who opposed her.
刃向かう者は「魔剣シュラムッフェン」の刃にかけ…
Excellent. Well done.
おりっ子　よくできました
Dragon Pneumonia and Shiron Byacornise...
龍骸咳とシロン＝ブーヤコーニッシュ
If the Church of Drowning in God's Grace
had them both, then well,
この二つが神溺教団の元に揃ってるってことは…
it doesn't take a genius
to figure that one out.
相当に鈍くても察しがつくわね
Luimon has already left for the Toatt Mine.
ルイモンさんはすでにドアット鉱山に向かえました
It's quite possible that he'll find
the missing Book fragments.
残りの「本」の欠片が発掘されるかもしれませんので
That's true. We should look for Shiron's first...
そうね　まずやるべきはシロンの…
Chief!
代行　神溺教団にいる哀れな人々の解放が先決です
Our first priority should be freeing those
poor folks from the Church's clutches!
Right now, they're...
今も彼らは…
Calm down, Volken. You'll spill your tea.
落ち着きなさい　ヴォルケン
こぼれちゃわよ
You can't drink it without honey, can you?
あっ　蜂蜜いるんだっけ？
Huh?
Volken!
ヴォルケン
The Chief's so immature...
代行も大人気ないなぁ
Volken, I understand how you feel.
ヴォルケン
気持ちは分かるわ
When I saw them, I felt the same way.
あれを見たら　私だって…
We have to act, to prevent certain disaster.
でもね　起こるであろう危機は
未然に防がなければならない
Yes, it's true the Chief has some
flaws in her personality...
代行は確かに　その
性格になんのあるのかもしれないげれと
But her powers cannot be denied.
でも　あの人の強さは本物だわ
We...
私たちは…
You always state the obvious.
お前はいつも分かりきったことを言う
Milepoc.
ミレポ
What?
なにを？
いつもすまない
I'm sorry for everything.
え？
もう
The Mines are heaven, or are they hell?
鉱山　天国それとも地獄？
後ろには　怖い武装司書
Scary Armed Librarians
waiting in the lurches...
But if we find that lovely girl's Book,
愛しい女の子が飛んでも出だら
キスを一つでもさせてくれ
let us give her a kiss!
What's your problem, kid?
なんだ　ガキ
Weirdo.
可笑しいな奴だな
Oh, they've made it all the way here?
おー　こんな所まで流れ着いたか
Book fragments, that is...
「本」の欠片か？
Whose Book is it? Where did you get it?
だれの「本」だ？
どこで手に入れた？
まぁ　いい
No matter. It's a far too
sophisticated toy for Meat.
「肉」には過ぎたおもちゃではあるが
Dead humans become Books.
死んだ人間は「本」になる
だが　お前の「本」は余白だらけだろうなぁ
Though the pages in yours will be blank...
Huh?
ハミュッツ＝メセタを殺せ
Kill Hamyuts Meseta.
Meat.
「肉」！
These are your things.
これがお前の荷物だ
俺たちは…
We're...
Kill Hamyuts Meseta.
ハミュッツ＝メセタを殺す
Ow!
痛ぇ　痛ぇよ
It hurts...
痛ぇ
Ow!
Yeah, it's festering.
あ　膿できてるようだ
Looks like the battle against the
Church of Drowning in God's Grace
神溺教団との戦いも　いよいよ本格化か
has finally begun in earnest.
ふんふん
紙臭い図書館で貸し出しカードを整理しているより
We're doing much more righteous acts
than managing library cards
in a musty, old library.
よっぽど正義の味方してるわよね
Would someone doing righteous
deeds deceive their friends?
正義の味方が仲間を欺くか？
Was it worth it, going there and doing all that,
そこまでしてあの場に赴いた収穫はあったのか？
oh fearless Chief?
館長代行様？
Oh, yeah... He might get my pulse up a bit.
そうね　ちょっとはドキドキさせてくれるかも
Hm?
え？
I may have found him.
見つけたかもしれない
The man who could kill me...
あたしを殺してくれる男わね
It has to be a mistake!
これは間違えた
I'm not a human whom someone could love.
僕は愛される人間じゃない
The reason being...
なぜなら
I'm not human.
僕は人間じゃない
あなたを愛してます
I love you.
Lost the light
Before closing the sun
If it's a sparkling storm
Jump in before it tempts
The end comes to everyone one day
When the day comes
Aim for the future that begins to move
Even if it's already been written
Search and even acquire the
meaning of getting hurt
In order to be myself
Bombs
爆弾と呼ばれた少年たちは
The boys they call bombs...
Bombs, a Princess
are made to explode in a
burst devoid of emotion.
Bombs, a Princess
空白の感情を破裂させていく
are made to explode in a
burst devoid of emotion.
Bombs, a Princess, and a Gray Town
灰色の街　赤の血
爆弹与公主和灰色街道
Crimson spills across a gray town.
Bombs, a Princess, and a Gray Town